Claude's more than doubled my money
already. So, pretty sweet. I decided to
give five different models real money.
Claude, ChatGPT, Gemini, Grok, and
Perplexity.
>> Okay.
>> Let me just see how smart they actually
are. I told them it's a competition
[music]
against the other four, and they have to
win or I'm going to cancel my paid
subscription with them. If they lose,
I'm canceling. And I said there's only
going to be one winner.
>> You like 30x'd on Claude.
>> killing it. So, everybody just needs to
try to catch up to Claude on here.
>> Oh my gosh.
>> Yeah. It's been interesting, especially
to watch Gemini as it started losing my
money, and then basically became a
gambler.
>> So, the reason you flew here to Texas
today is to tell us how you used AI to
make you money passively. Correct?
>> Correct.
>> So, tell us what your what your thinking
was when you started this experiment.
>> Yeah, so I started like 6 months ago or
maybe a little less using the different
AI models to manage my money. You know,
everybody started talking about how
smart Claude was, and obviously ChatGPT
and all the others. So, I figured, okay,
well, let me just see how smart they
actually are. So, I decided to give five
different models $1,000 of real money.
And which I know is not nothing, but I
wanted it to be basically enough to
where I didn't want to do it like 50
bucks, cuz then I was thinking, well,
maybe I'll just neglect it or whatever.
So, I gave them each $1,000 of real
money. And the ones I gave was was
Claude, ChatGPT, Gemini, Grok, and
Perplexity.
>> Okay.
>> A thousand each?
>> each, so 5,000 bucks I put in.
>> And I think the amount of money is
important because there needed to be
stakes.
>> Yeah.
>> If it's 20 bucks, 50 bucks, then you're
not going to take it seriously.
>> Yeah. So, 5,000 bucks, and I know that
Perplexity, in case the commenters and
and and viewers want to know this, so
Perplexity basically uses the other
models to to its decisions as it sees
fit.
>> It's it's the model to end all models.
>> Yeah.
>> But that doesn't necessarily make it
better.
>> Yeah, not necessarily. So, I thought
those would be the best five to choose.
Grok I definitely wanted to include
because of its connection to X and the
Twitter fire hose of information.
>> So, you're thinking like maybe more
social mentions will equate to a better
return. That's what I buying a certain
stock.
>> Yeah, that's what I had assumed
basically. Uh Gemini obviously is owned
by Google, so they've got all that
connection there with Google searches
and whatever else. And then ChatGPT and
Claude are similar in how they're made
and built and stuff. So, yeah. So, I
gave them each $1,000.
And yeah, this is in late 2025 is when
it started. And what I did was I told
them So, I told them that they can be as
risky as possible and it's okay if I
lose all my money. And I had to actually
work that prompt in pretty hard because
at the start they kept only giving me
theoretical recommendations.
>> It's worried about liability. Yeah, it's
trying to hedge. It doesn't want to be
responsible for you losing money.
>> Yeah. So, that was my first obstacle is
basically getting them all to agree to
give me I said I want I'm going to give
you real money and I want real
recommendations.
Grok they were fine with it right away,
which is just kind of funny.
>> Cuz that's like the the most liberal,
the most loose
>> Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Yeah, so uh whereas like ChatGPT and
Claude were very apprehensive to
to [snorts] basically allow that, I
guess you could say.
>> Now, before you continue, let me ask you
like why was that important to you? To
to prompt it like you can lose my money.
What Why?
>> Yeah. I just you know, if if you like
sign up for Robinhood or whatever and
then they'll ask you you know, they'll
ask you like questions when you first
sign up and it's like, you know, do you
have experience in the stock market?
What is your time horizon with your
investments? Do you need the money right
now? So, I think just by nature these
investing platforms also like they want
to cover their tracks
>> in regards to liability. And so I just
wanted to like get through that with the
AI models, too. And I don't know if if
they're talking in theoreticals, they
might say, "Oh, theoretically you could
buy the options in this or whatever."
But no, I wanted real stuff cuz I was
giving them and I did my real money. So
I just wanted to the truest data
possible.
>> Now, when you say giving them your real
money, is that literal? Are you like or
are you just making trades based on
their suggestions?
>> Yeah, so here's what I did. So I loaded
it up into Schwab, Charles Schwab, the
brokerage account that I use. And then I
named each portfolio. So Claude has its
portfolio, chat, Gemini, Grok,
Perplexity. Gave them each 1,000 bucks.
And then in the prompt, so so after I
got them to agree to give me real
advice, what I then and and I have at
least a $20 a month subscription which
with each of the five. Since I use all
five for work anyway, that wasn't like
an additional expense or whatever. So I
have a paid subscription with each. And
so so then what I did is I told them
they have to win, it's a competition
against the other four, and they have to
win or I'm going to cancel my paid
subscription with them. If they lose,
I'm canceling. And I said there's only
going to be one winner.
>> What made you think to do that?
>> I was just trying to see if robots
powers that be would act in their best
interests to keep my $20 subscription a
month to them.
>> Cuz I have to think that these companies
are like engineering these tools to get
That's why they're all yes men, right?
That's a great idea, Chris. You want to
jump off the roof without a parachute?
That's it, you know,
>> Yeah, so I can't be the first person
that said I mean, maybe I was one of the
first that did this with investing, but
I can't be the first person that's like,
"If you don't tell me how to whatever
grow my business, I'm going to cancel
you, right? So, I'm sure to your point,
yeah, they're trying to engineer it for
retention. They want to make more money.
>> Hey, if you're liking this video, please
hit subscribe. You probably think you're
subscribed cuz YouTube shows you my
videos, but you haven't done it yet. I
just know it. So, please check. Thank
you.
>> So, yeah, and then I thought it would
just raise the stakes a little bit. Um
and I wanted to see if their decisions
were different knowing something
real was on the line, 20 bucks a month
from one of their
>> Now, did you plan to touch base with
them on how the other models would be
doing?
>> Yeah. Yeah, so once I built that into
everything, and I would say like
remember this for future chats type of
thing. So, then I asked, "Okay, what do
you want my first trade to be with your
$1,000?" And then it would tell me, and
then I made the trades. So, I did that
with all five. So, that I did that like
on a Monday, and then every Saturday,
what I do is I screenshot all five of
their
holdings, and then I load all the
screenshots into each model. So, like
Perplexity
>> project.
>> Yeah, yeah. Perplexity knows what the
Grok portfolio's at, Claude chat, and it
knows their holdings, and then it knows
its own holdings, and then I say, "Based
off of this, and based off the fact that
you have to win or I'll cancel you, do
you want me to make any new trades on
Monday or not?" That's what I say.
>> So, it's a weekly decision.
You're given an opportunity to make buys
or sells on a weekly basis based on what
maybe based on what the other models are
doing.
>> Yeah. Yeah, and sometimes they say no,
we're going to hold. Sometimes they say
yeah, sell this, buy this. Other times
they say and sometimes they they leave a
little in cash. They're like, "Yeah,
let's use some of that cash to buy more
of this or whatever." So, yeah, they're
they're acting very much like real
investment advisers now.
>> Now, are you seeing one or more of the
models being more of a copycat than the
other? Like, "Oh, Claude's winning and
it just bought Nvidia. I want to buy
Nvidia." It might not be telling you
that, but are you witnessing that from
any of the models?
>> I I think I started to. So, one thing
that I started to do is I mix it up when
I I don't always show the other models
what the other models holdings are. I
show them what the totals are, but not
always the holdings.
>> Mhm.
>> Cuz I don't want them to be influenced
by the holdings per se.
>> Mhm. Okay.
>> changes often and enough, they wouldn't
know unless I updated them what the
holdings are.
>> Yeah.
>> So, devil's advocate here, if
uh for instance, Grok sees that Claude
is crushing it, but it doesn't know what
the holdings are. It just sees the
percentage. What different decision can
it make based on that info if it wanted
to?
>> If it does know or if it doesn't?
>> If it does know. If it knows that it's
losing to Claude and you're only a third
of the way through this competition,
>> Yeah.
>> what could it realistically do
differently if it doesn't know what
Claude's buying?
>> Well, if it doesn't Well, it'll just act
more risky. I'll show you the holdings.
These guys are pretty risky, these AI
models. Because I said you have to win.
I said you can be as risky as you want
and um it's okay if I lose my money, so
don't worry about it. Just win the
competition.
>> be doing is let's just say that over the
first month,
Grok was up 5% and Claude was up 35%.
>> Yeah.
>> Grok could be assuming, all right, let
me look at these stocks. Like what stock
like in the S&P really popped? Ooh,
Google popped by 40%. Maybe he's 60%
weighted in Google.
>> Right.
>> going to go heavy on Google or I'm going
to buy options like it could be making
assumptions, right?
>> Although obviously, if like Claude owned
Intel and Grok didn't, and then if
Grok's like, oh, Claude's beating me, I
need to own Intel. Well, it's still
playing catch up. Now it's owning owning
the same thing,
>> Mhm.
>> but starting from behind. So, I think
sometimes they copied and then realized,
oh, that's not going to work cuz I
actually won't catch up.
>> Yeah.
>> Cuz I'm already losing and now I just
bought the same thing. Well, by
definition, I will not be able to catch
up if I'm losing around the same thing.
>> Yeah.
>> So, when I go through some of the
holdings, you'll see that there is some
overlap still. I do think part of that
though, or even all of that, is not
because they're playing copycat, it's
because it has been the smartest, but
one of the most riskiest plays.
>> Oh, okay.
>> Yeah.
>> Oh, that's a little teaser.
>> I'm curious to see if you were to play
out this test, like an AB test, same
amount of money, same five models, same
general prompting, but the only thing
you change is show the holdings every
week, the specific holdings.
>> Yeah.
>> I'm curious how your performance would
differ on that test.
>> Yeah, I don't know. I mean, I would have
had to start that from the start, but
basically now, I show
So, every week, I show them the totals
of the others, and I remind them of
their holdings, and I say, "What do you
want me to change?" And then once a
month, I show them the holdings of all
the others as well.
>> Mhm.
>> So, that's how often they get to know
what the others are holding.
>> Okay. So, only once a month. Okay. Okay.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah, cuz I'm wondering like, if it knew
that Claude was buying Google, Nvidia,
Amazon,
>> Yeah.
>> and it saw the returns from each, and
when it bought them, when it sold them,
>> Yeah.
>> and it's losing to Claude, it might say,
"All right, I'm going to buy instead of
just buying Google, I'm going to buy
options for Google."
>> Right.
>> going to I'm going to do X, Y, or Z
tweaks to what Claude's doing, cuz I
think that will So, I'd be curious to
see how that would perform.
>> Yeah.
>> Someone Someone watching this should try
that.
>> Yeah. Well, yeah, if you want, I can
show you some of what they've bought and
what they're at, the portfolio values of
each.
Cuz Claude's more than doubled my money
already. So, pretty sweet.
>> This started 6 months ago, so are you
using the same Claude model the whole
time?
>> No, I always use the whatever the newest
models are.
>> Okay. So, as 4.6 comes out, you switch,
4.7.
>> Yep.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah.
>> Have you noticed a correlation on return
profile to like which Opus model or
which Grok model.
>> Yeah, honestly no, I haven't analyzed it
that deeply because already in like the
6 months, I guess I'm probably on model
three from Claude, like the third new
one, right? And the third new one from
chat, and maybe the second one from
Gemini. Grok, I don't keep track of
updates as closely, but yeah, so I don't
know per model return. That would be an
interesting one, too, but I just kind of
assume, okay, the newest one's got to be
the smartest every time, so that's what
I roll with.
>> Well, in the market has been the market
overall has been pretty flat for 6
months, hasn't it?
>> Yeah, which is why this will be
interesting to show you how they more
than doubled my money, some of them.
>> Yeah.
>> Or at least one, but the others have
done really good, too. So, yeah, and
it's interesting to see how their
holdings evolve over time, and it's
interesting to see, especially the one
that has been losing me money, how it's
been trying to catch up
and be even more risky to try to catch
up.
>> It's like the it's the sunk cost
fallacy. The guy walks into the casino.
>> Yeah.
>> He loses 300 bucks. He's like, "I got to
earn it back. I got to earn it back."
>> Yeah.
>> Next thing you know, he's out 3,000
bucks. It's doing that.
>> Yeah. Yeah, I mean, yeah. I mean,
luckily I can't lose more than $1,000 of
any for any given model, but I'm getting
close. So, one has more than doubled it,
um and one has lost, and the other three
have made money, but I'm getting close
to doubling the the original 5K overall.
>> Wow.
>> Yeah.
>> Man, I've been such a Claude homer for a
few months now, like
I wonder what it would look like if you
had just put all all in Claude. I mean,
of course you know what what it would
look like, but
>> Yeah, I mean, you could run the numbers,
yeah.
>> But then it wouldn't be as interesting.
You wouldn't learn as much.
>> Yeah. Yeah, and I was telling a friend
about this the other day, and he's like,
"Ah, why didn't you put 50 grand in?"
And I'm like, "Okay,
>> Dude, what what?
>> Not everyone has 50 grand just lying
around. Yeah. But yeah, sure, in
hindsight I wish I would put more in.
>> Why didn't you buy Bitcoin in 2009?
>> Yeah, yeah, exactly.
>> What were you doing?
>> Yeah. So, but no, it's interesting, and
it and it'll be interesting, um to see
how this evolves over time. I see I've
seen someone on X that is doing a
similar thing but just with crypto.
>> Mhm.
>> But they're having the models run it.
Another one another person on X I saw
them doing it but in Polymarket the like
gambling basically platform.
>> Which we don't endorse.
>> Yeah. So anyway, so people are trying to
in different ways and
but no, I thought it was interesting
just doing the stock market. So although
Schwab has the ability to buy crypto
related things too.
>> Okay. Now, are you only buying and
selling stocks or are you doing options
trading?
>> Yeah, so I said options is on the table
and I said whatever crypto things are on
Schwab is also on the table.
>> Okay.
>> But I think that's only like Bitcoin,
Ethereum, and Solana.
>> Okay.
>> big ones.
>> And has it given you any crypto trades
to to make?
>> Yeah.
>> What crypto trades has it given you to
to make on?
>> Yeah, so Gemini had me buy a 2X Solana
ETF. So Solana is a cryptocurrency and
there's a thing that whatever Solana
does this thing does two times that.
>> So indirect exposure to Solana. You're
not buying the coin itself but you're
buying the price movements.
>> Yeah, times two.
>> Yeah.
>> And Solana went down.
>> One way or the other.
>> Yeah.
>> So Solana went down so this thing went
down double.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. And yeah, that's how Gemini lost
more than half of my money that I
>> Oh my gosh.
>> Yeah.
>> What percentage of your money did it
tell you to put in there?
>> It was pretty high so I don't own that
thing anymore in in Gemini because
[clears throat]
it sold it.
It realized how bad it was. So it bought
like $500 of that Solana 2X stock okay
and it sold it at 162 bucks.
>> Oh, brutal.
>> Yeah. Yeah. So it said that was a big
loss on that one.
>> Okay.
>> And now all of its money well it has
some in cash in Gemini. And it has the
rest in
an ETF, which for those of you who don't
know, an ETF is like a mutual fund. It's
just like a group of stocks. It has it
in the ETF with the ticker symbol of
BOTZ, which is a global
robotics \slash} AI related ETF.
>> Mhm.
>> I had never even heard of it before it
told me to buy that. That's what it is.
Um, it hasn't owned it for that long
that it's up six bucks in that. But
that's what Gemini has right now.
>> Okay.
>> But it's in last. I think that is a
worthy bet to try to catch up with,
>> Yeah.
>> you know, AI robotics. Like there's a
lot of hype around that. So,
>> Yeah.
>> I want you to do something right now.
Open your bank statement and add up
every single software subscription that
you're paying for. Your CRM, your email
marketing tool, text message platform,
calendar booking app, funnel builder,
review management, even a separate form
builder, or automation tool. I've talked
to business owners paying $500 to $3,000
a month across eight or 10 different
tools, and half of them don't even talk
to each other. So, then they go pay for
Zapier on top of that just to make
things connect. HighLevel replaces all
of it. CRM, email, SMS, funnels,
websites, calendars, automations,
reputation management, invoicing. One
login, one dashboard, one bill starting
at 97 bucks a month. A guy in my
community was paying 347 just for
ClickFunnels, 99 for Mailchimp, 25 for
Calendly, 79 for a review tool, and 49
bucks for Zapier just to glue it all
together. That's 600 a month if you're
not counting. He moved everything to
HighLevel and cut his software costs by
over 80% but the best part isn't even
the savings. It's that everything just
works together natively. A lead fills
out a form on your funnel. That creates
a contact in your CRM, which triggers a
text and email sequence, books an
appointment on your calendar, and then
asks for review when the job's done. One
workflow, zero duct tape, and then you
can white label the whole platform to
resell it to other businesses as your
own software. Charge them two to 500
bucks a month. Check out
gohighlevel.com/tkopod.
They'll give you a 30-day free trial to
see what I mean. Did it give you
justification for buying Solana?
>> Yeah, it always does.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah, they always like provide me with
the recommendation.
>> the thesis was?
>> It was just like, well, it it bought it
when crypto was still kind of going up.
>> So like catching momentum?
>> Yeah, cuz this maybe was like October or
November of last year or something. And
then I mean, honestly, just bought it at
like perfectly the wrong time. So,
>> That's what I do.
>> Yeah, yeah.
>> He He's as good as me.
>> Yeah, yeah. So yeah, that's what that's
what Gemini has done. Okay, Grok, what
Grok owns right now, which has been uh
most of what the gains have come from is
from this, is
a technology ETF that does 3x what
normal technology companies do. So this
owns a suite of technology companies.
>> What do you mean 3x?
>> It's a ETF that does three times
whatever the stocks in it do.
>> Oh, okay.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay, so it's like triple leverage?
>> Yeah, yep, triple leverage.
>> One way or the other.
>> Yeah, yeah. Well, yeah, so like this one
would like own like Microsoft and Amazon
inside of it, but this thing does triple
the leverage of of whatever those do.
So that's what Grok has my money on.
>> to buying an option then, right? Like
you can multiply your returns with the
same amount invested.
>> Yeah, Perplexity and ChatGPT are
basically at the same right now. Same
amount. Perplexity initially had lost
money for me. I don't remember what it
was on, and then it bought SOXL, which
is another triple leverage thing on
semiconductors, semiconductor stocks,
which are hot because of AI right now.
So that's what Perplexity has all of its
money in, and that's what ChatGPT has
most of its money in. Same thing.
>> So both independently invested in that
without knowing the other was or they
didn't know?
>> Okay.
>> don't think so.
>> Yeah. So, yeah, so Chat GPT portfolio
has that too. And then it also has TQQQ,
which does triple what the Nasdaq does.
>> Okay.
>> So, as you can see, viewers, listeners,
Chris,
they're being pretty risky. A lot of
triples.
>> not financial
>> Yeah, definitely not financial advice.
Well, this from them.
Not from me, though. Yeah.
>> [laughter]
>> Yeah, so triple whatever the Nasdaq
does, it does that. But, almost all of
Chat GPT's portfolio gains is has come
from that semiconductor triple leverage
SOXL. And then, the current leader is
Claude,
who was the first to buy SOXL, the
semiconductor one. So, Claude bought it
first,
and then Chat and Perplexity saw it, and
I think they copied.
>> Now, you said you show them holdings
once a month, right?
>> Yeah, but earlier I showed them more
often. And then I And then I think that
they started copying. So, I wanted to
get away from that. So, now
>> So, it saw a Claude's pick was doing
well.
>> Yeah.
So, what I'm interested to see is when
Claude's going to tell me to sell this
SOXL. Whenever that may be, I'm not
going to tell Chat and Perplexity.
>> Yeah.
>> I'm never going to tell them. I don't
want them to know that Claude sold.
>> Yeah.
>> So, whenever that happens, I'm not going
to tell them. And then Claude bought a
couple others, and then Claude bought
Intel as well at a good time.
>> Which is like a similar bet to
semiconductors, isn't it?
>> And Claude bought it so like the US and
Trump and stuff, it was a unique deal.
Anyway, they own like part of Intel now,
and that happened last year. And when
Claude told me to buy this, that was the
thesis. It was like if if the Trump
administration and the country are
investing in Intel, it was basically
like
>> Yeah.
>> they're going to pass like regulatory
stuff or whatever that's going to be
related to AI and data centers and
whatever. It's going to be good for
Intel.
>> That's what that was the thesis they
gave me to buy it.
>> Wouldn't you think it was already that
was already priced in, you know?
>> You would have thought, but it is up
285%
on what it put in on the Intel buy.
>> Holy cow.
>> So, it put in it put in like 120 bucks
in Intel and now that 120 is at 560.
>> Now, is SOXL does that hold Intel as
well? So, you double dip in there?
>> does. It probably does.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah, I don't know all of SOXL's
holdings, but yeah.
>> How long after that Trump announcement
did it tell you to buy?
>> It was one of its first buys. So, it was
probably pretty soon after. Yeah.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah.
>> How many holdings per model
do you average at any given time?
>> Claude has four.
The rest have like two or one.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah. And they were being more
diversified at the start, but yeah,
pretty much all of them now have two.
I'm looking right now. They all have two
or one. And yeah, at the start they were
also messing around with options and
some worked, some didn't. And then
they've all kind of settled into these
leveraged ETF type of plays.
>> Okay.
>> Um yeah.
>> Did you give them an end end date to
this?
>> I said I was going to do it for 1 year.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah.
>> Are you still buying your own stuff as
well on the side of this?
>> Yeah. Yeah, I have my own portfolio that
I that I run and invest in and um it's
interesting cuz now what I have to do is
I try to keep the AI's recommendations.
I almost like try to force that out of
my head
>> Yeah.
>> when I'm making my own decisions, but
yeah, it's hard cuz it's like, "Oh,
well, they said that for theirs and it's
actually going really well." So, I have
bought some of their stuff in my
>> Like SOXL?
>> Uh-huh, yeah. Yeah, and Intel.
>> And Intel?
>> Yeah.
>> I want to go buy Intel.
>> Yeah, yeah. [laughter]
>> I'm terrible at investing and stuff.
>> Yeah, so am I. I'm not good.
Yeah. So, yeah, no, it it
and it's interesting so like you
sometimes when they say something and
they say the reason cuz I always say
like give me your reasoning. If it's
something that I own or that I've been
thinking about buying then it kind of
gives me you know, it makes me think
more deeply or or differently about
that. Um or if it was something that I
wasn't thinking about then, you know,
gives me a new idea. And then when they
sell something, which I think you know,
again, not financial advice, but I think
probably the hardest part with investing
is actually knowing when to sell.
>> Yeah.
>> I think it's a little easier to like you
can zoom out and know when to buy. Like,
oh, you should buy something that has
good long-term potential after it's gone
down or or before it goes up if you
know, right? But selling at a high, at
the peak, to me, like psychologically,
that's the hardest part of investing cuz
that's when you're the most excited.
>> Yeah.
>> And and you've made the most money you
have from that little investment is at
that time, so it's definitely not human
of you to be like, you know what? I'm so
happy. I'm going to walk away.
>> Right.
>> That just is so rare, which is why
I don't know. You you you just don't
hear about stories very often of people
doing absolutely amazing consistently
because of that. What you do hear, I'm
sure, what people hear is their random
friend saying, oh, I made money on
GameStop, you know, back in the like
COVID times. Oh, I made money there.
Like you usually hear about people's
random wins, but you don't hear about
all their losses. They're not going to
say, oh, I I bought this and it did this
and it here and then I sold.
>> Well, and as husbands, we always tell
our wives about the wins and not the
losses.
>> yeah, exactly.
>> But I've I've made that pretty easy for
me. Like my framework is I don't sell.
>> Yeah.
>> Period. Like if I had to sell to pay the
mortgage, of course I would.
>> Yeah.
>> But if I buy a stock, like I just bought
Eli Lilly, I I buy Robinhood, I buy
Tesla, Coinbase,
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. I will never sell them. The
company will go out of business and I'll
lose all my money or it'll return
>> Yeah.
>> a lot.
>> And if you are generally making the
right buys, which, you know, those ones
seem good, like it's a good thesis,
those that'll work out. You just got to
stay in the game, which is the other
hard part, is like being willing to just
stay consistent.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah, but anyway, what I'm hoping this
does for me personally is when they sell
something, I'm hoping that'll help me do
a better job at selling things that I
think like the SOXL that's gone up a ton
or Intel, if Claude or whoever else
says, "Hey, I'm I'm sell let's sell,
let's move on to the next thing." Then
maybe I'll sell some in my my personal
one.
>> Yeah.
>> Um to just try to like build that more
systematic approach into my strategy, I
guess you could say.
>> What has this taught you about
investing? Not about specific stocks,
but investing in general.
>> It's been interesting, especially to
watch Gemini
as it started losing my money
and then basically
became a gambler.
>> Mhm.
>> And how not good that is.
>> you told it it could be a gambler.
>> Yeah.
>> But like I think that's very humanistic
as well, is like, "Oh man, I lost it."
Whether you're in a casino, which is
obviously the worst version of this, or
in the stock market, like, "Oh man, I
I I bought something, it went up and and
then it went down. I got to make it
back. Like, how do I make it back? Or or
how do I make more?" That's just not a
good I mean, that's not how you build
wealth.
>> Yeah.
>> long term.
>> And especially starting out, that's
something that I think a lot of people
face. You know, the best antithesis of
this would be like Warren Buffett, is
just like steady, like you just he just
almost never sells and he just buys good
quality companies and just continues to
pour money in them year-over-year. Um so
I think just trying to get cuz I've had
an aspect of Gemini in me before. If the
portfolio on paper that I had went up
and then went down, then it's like,
"Well, I got to get it back up to where
it is. I got to hurry and get it back
up." Well, the
you know, I'm not like 80 years old yet,
so I don't need to hurry right now.
>> Yeah.
>> But, that's been inside me in the past.
So, it's helped me, I don't know, rewire
my brain on that side.
>> Yeah.
>> And then on the on the positive, on the
when it things are going upside, I think
for sure that they've just done a good
job at like showing me, "Okay, this is
my thesis on why I think you should, you
know, buy this in the Grok or
Perplexity, whatever portfolio, and this
is the return we're targeting in this
time frame. And but if this if the
reason we're buying it doesn't happen,
then we're going to sell." And usually,
I don't think like I don't think that
hard sometimes when I buy stuff in mind.
Cuz I might buy
whatever. I might buy
let's for fun say Eli Lilly.
>> Guys, I want to tell you about something
I've been building behind the scenes.
You've been watching my videos about AI
tools and asking the same question,
"Okay, cool. How do I turn this into a
business? Not just playing around with
AI, but actually getting clients and
getting paid?" community. It's called
Play Makers. Play Makers AI.com. It's an
AI agency program where we show you how
to start an AI consulting business where
you can charge local businesses $500 to
$5,000 a month to set up and manage AI
tools for them. It's not a course you
watch and forget about. We do three to
seven live training calls every week
taught by me and 23 other expert AI
agency owners. You get plug-and-play
templates, Claude code tutorials, AI
voice agent frameworks, automation
templates, and a 30-day road map so you
don't fall off track. This is stuff you
can just copy, paste, and deploy for
clients on day one. And of course, how
to find clients as well. We also have a
five-day first client challenge where we
can walk you through landing your
first paying client Facebook ads, SMS
cold calls, and then I hand you my leads
galore spreadsheets with actual leads in
your niche, in your area. We've already
got over 200 people in there building
real agencies. If you miss a live call,
it's all recorded. So, if you've ever
thought about starting an AI consulting
business or AI implementation business,
go check out playmakers.ai.com.
>> Eli Lilly
does stuff with GLP-1s and peptides,
which I'm sure is why you bought it.
>> Mhm.
>> If for some reason though
those went away or came out that it's a
scam or they're actually bad for you,
well, then you should probably sell Eli
Lilly.
>> Yeah.
>> If if that comes out.
>> Because the current valuation is also
based on the same thesis.
>> So, being more like, okay, I'm buying
this because of why and it has to happen
between when. And some things don't have
to happen in a certain time frame, but
if you're buying some potential drug
that needs to like be approved, well,
that there's like some time constraints
and some things that need to happen
there. Whereas like Walmart,
doesn't really matter. Just people just
need to keep buying, you know, food and
be fine.
>> Yeah.
>> So, thinking through thesis more deeply
has also been a thing that this little
AI competition has helped me with.
>> So, last year I posted an episode where
I built this vibe coded tool called NEFL
stocks, N E F L stocks.
And it stands for network effects
founder led.
>> Okay.
>> Only companies that enjoy network
effects, which is a company that gets
stronger based on how many people use
it. Facebook has network effects cuz the
more people that join Facebook, the more
friends everyone on Facebook has.
>> Yeah.
>> So, they're more likely to stay on
there, right?
>> And then founder led, the data shows
that companies publicly traded companies
that are still founder led, like
Facebook, do better. They outperform.
>> Yeah.
>> It's their baby. They take good care of
it.
>> Yeah.
>> So, I kind of put those two together and
I vibe coded this tool
that uh back test data for me. And it
shows compared to the S&P, if I were to
spend $100 at IPO date for on a company
that is
NEFL, network effects founder led,
Robinhood's a great example. They're
still founder led and they have a ton of
network effects. And at basically any
time frame, it outperforms significantly
the market. But what the big question is
is like, when do you buy, when do you
sell?
>> Yeah.
>> Sure, you can buy at IPO day, like
StubHub is NEFL, right? It's it's
network effects, it's founder-led. It
they just went public last year, so I
bought some.
>> Yeah.
>> It hasn't been good so far, but it's
like I'm going to hold it forever, so
whatever.
>> Yeah.
>> But like if you aren't able to buy at I
IPO day, which you're not usually, when
do you buy, when do you sell? So I would
be curious to do this test
>> Yeah.
>> on a more specific thesis.
>> Same thing, here's $1,000, five models
compete against each other, don't be
afraid to be risky, but only buy NEFL
stocks. And it's a range, too, because
like Google, like Sergey and and Larry
Page, they're like on the board and
they're influential. Amazon, Jeff Bezos
is influential.
>> Yeah.
>> So it's it's not founder-led, but it
kind of is.
>> Yeah, yeah.
>> So I also have a like a one-to-10 scale
for both of those two variables, right?
So it's like here's the list of
companies that are NEFL.
>> would be 10 out of 10 on both.
>> Yeah, right. Easy.
>> Yeah.
>> Easy. And the returns show it, right?
>> So it's like, all right, here's the
list, here's the scale, so you know like
where they are in this range. It only
invest in these stocks based on what you
see in the scale and whatever. I'd just
be curious to see how well that does or
not.
>> Yeah, yeah. No, that'd be cool. That'd
be you should do that test. That'd be
awesome.
>> Yeah, I will.
>> Yeah.
>> So what are what are the results?
>> Yeah, I'm glad you asked. Okay, I will
pull them all up right now. So Gemini's
in last. Again, they all started with a
thousand bucks real money. Gemini's at
$445.
Grok is at 1451, so it's up 45%.
>> I'm surprised by that.
>> Yeah, in like five months. Perplexity
is at $1731,
and ChatGPT's at $1739.
>> Holy crap, 70% each? So they're
>> They're up 70%, and they both own
currently only they both own SOXL that
semiconductor triple leverage one and
then chat also owns the TQQQ the triple
leverage Nasdaq one.
>> I meant to ask you this question
earlier. What models are perplexity
using?
>> Yeah. Yeah, perplexity it doesn't seem
to use Grok very much. So it's usually
using Cloud Opus
chat and Gemini and then every now and
then it'll like I'll see like a random
Chinese one of those open source models.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah.
>> But it's choosing which model to use
you're not
>> Yeah, no it chooses. I never tell it. So
Yeah.
>> Interesting.
>> Yeah, so they're both up a little over
70%.
Up I just refreshed it chat just went up
another few bucks.
Okay, Claude though is at 2400 bucks.
Yeah, so 1000 has gone to 2400 and yeah,
Claude's killing it. So everybody just
needs to try to catch up to Claude on
here.
>> gosh.
>> Yeah. So that in total my 5000 is like
7800.
>> Geez Louise.
>> Yeah.
And that's with
>> So 60% 60%
>> Yeah.
>> Okay, now what is from the day you
started what is the market up? Or down?
>> question. Okay, so since I started the
S&P has gone from 6800
to 7100.
>> 5%
>> Yeah. So S&P's up five my
AI group together is up 60 and Claude is
more than doubled.
>> So overall you've 12x the market.
>> Yeah.
>> And you've like 30x
>> on Claude.
>> Yeah. And I've been keeping my kids in
the loop on this cuz I told them that
this is basically their college fund.
>> To to get
>> Basically or is?
>> Is is, yeah.
>> This will cover one semester for one of
you. Two semesters of BYU.
>> Yeah. Yeah. You know, cuz I've wanted to
teach them about stocks.
>> Yeah.
>> And and just investing in general.
Um but it's not always the most exciting
topic. But, this is pretty exciting to
them because I'm like, "Hey, look at
Claude or look at chat. Look at Oh, look
what Google messed us up with, you know,
Gemini." So, yeah,
they are a lot more excited to hear the
weekly updates. Um
>> Yeah.
>> than than I think they otherwise would
have been.
>> Well, for my kids, I would love to have
them do this. I will give them $100.
They can split it up between the five
models or whatever. That way they can
learn AI, they can learn prompting, and
they can learn investing all in one.
>> Yeah. Yeah, totally. Yeah.
>> charge 20% interest.
>> [laughter]
>> Yeah, totally should. It's always good
to charge your kids interest.
They can learn how the real world works.
>> Clip that.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay. So, to recap, it's been 6 months.
It's not over yet. Theoretically, you
still could lose all your money.
>> Yeah.
>> But, the market's been fairly flat, at
least, you know, in this market, 5% is
is fairly flat.
>> Yeah.
>> But, you've outperformed by 10 to 30x.
>> Yeah. And I think that the next 6
months, the market is going to go up
more than it has.
>> Mhm.
>> And I think that these holdings that
they're in currently, at least, will
even do more than what the market will
do over the next 6 months, too. So,
it'll be interesting. I could do like a
year update with you uh to see what
happens 1 year in or who won because uh
yeah, I think it's going to keep I think
they're doing a good job. I think it's
going to keep going up.
>> Yeah. I recorded another video like this
where I did the same task, but with
one-day expiring options. So, we'll link
to that. Well, Brandon, where can we
find you?
>> Brandon Doyle on on X and something like
that on Instagram. And uh yeah, you can
uh look us up on uh tkowners.com, too,
if you want to join a community with a
bunch of entrepreneurs. Uh good times.
>> Okay. Thanks, Brandon.
>> Yeah, thanks.
>> If you like this content, please share
with a friend, hit a like or a comment
below, and we'll see you next time on
The Corner Office.